SULEMAN LAKHANI

Henrico, VA sulemanlakhani73@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/suleman-lakhani-84820794/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Tech-savvy Mobile Automation Test Engineer with established test case creation and execution talents. Comprehensive experience in both manual and automated testing with a great understanding of the software development process. Superb consulting and communication skills. Strong communication and interaction with clients, developers, business analysts, and management. Proven ability in working individually or as a part of team. Problem solving, process improvement activities, analytical, and reporting skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science May 2022

Major: Computer Science Randolph-Macon College, Ashland, VA

Minor: Cyber Security

Associate of Science August 2019

Major: Mathematics Reynolds Community College, Richmond, VA

Honors: Cum Laude

Associate of Science December 2018

Major: Computer Science Reynolds Community College, Richmond, VA

Honors: Magna Cum Laude

Honors

President's List • Dean's List • Susan Lynn Pahle Memorial Scholarship • McCormick Scholarship • Mary Morton Parsons Endowed Scholarship • Early Childhood Development Volunteer • Member of Phi Theta Kappa (International Honor Society)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JAVA, Python, C/C++, Groovy
- Rest APIs: BrainShop API
- Relational Database: PostgreSQL
- Operating Systems: Windows XP/7/8/10/11, Mac OS, fedora Linux, Ubuntu
- MS Office Tools: Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, MS Access
- Experience with Google Suites (Slides, Sheets, Docs)
- Browser Automation: Internet Explorer, Google Chrome
- Testing Tools: Appium, Selenium, TestNG, JUnit, jEdit, Soap UI, Postman, RESTful, Android Studio, Eclipse IDE, Real devices, Android Emulator,
- Testing Types: Mobile and Web Application Testing, Integration Testing
- Build & Integration Tools: Maven, Jenkins, Headspin, Nexus Repository, Git
- Project Management Tool: JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Capstone Project

Randolph-Macon College

February 2022 – April 2022

• Created an Android Chatbot Application using BrainShop AI which performs mood detection based on user input keywords and suggests a playlist of songs based on the mood detected.

- Performed lead role to oversee the development of the application.
- Performed a live demonstration of the application and presentation for the Capstone Committee as wells as students.
- Performed UI functional testing of the android application on real devices as well as android emulator.
- Participated in the design and development of the application starting with wire frame, followed by developing the activities and integrating the BrainShop API into the application.
- Performed API testing using Postman to check API responses for specific API requests
- Application developed Smart Music
- Resources used: Android Studio, Postman, Git, Java Object-oriented Programming, Android Documentation, REST API, BrainShop API, Real devices and Android Emulator.

Computer Science Intern

Black Pond LLC, Burke, VA / Ashland Town FC, Ashland VA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Provided the expertise to utilize data integration, data management, and technical support.
- Worked on the Ashland Town FC website to enhance the new player registration experience by embedding google forms on the webpage.
- Provided technical support for website upkeep and passed that knowledge on to management for continued improvements

Software Development Test Engineer

Kohl's Innovation Center, Menomonee Falls, WI

December 2019 - March 2020

- Worked with an Android Development and Testing team to migrate current in-store Applications used by associates from Windows platform to Android OS
- Learned how to assess performance and outcomes on a set schedule to continuously improve with each new cycle
- Created Appium Scripts for native Android/ Apps using JAVA client library
- Performed UI functional testing for each build or version using target devices., Headspin (cloud-based emulators) and Real devices using TestNG, Selenium and with the extension of Appium and Java as client library
- Implemented cross-browser testing with Selenium WebDriver
- Developed BDD script with Cucumber and written step definition for Gherkin based features
- Worked in an Agile environment
- Tracked, prioritized, and organized defects in Jira, working with the development team to facilitate timely corrections
- In-store Applications worked on MLS Management, MLS Fulfillment, MLS Replenishment

Sales Associate

Follett Higher Education Group Inc., Richmond, VA

August 2016 - October 2016

- Monitored sales floor and merchandise displays for presentable condition, taking corrective action such as restocking or reorganizing products
- Balanced and organized cash register by handling cash, counting change, and storing coupons
- Answered product questions with up-to-date knowledge of sales and store promotions
- Helped customers locate items and join reward programs to promote loyalty, satisfaction, and sales numbers